YMCA ARMED SERVICES DEPARTMENT:
University of Minnesota Libraries
- Administrative Files
  - Local Club Files:
    - Temple, TX, insurance, 1965-1973. (Box 115)
    - Temple, TX, meetings, 1971-1973. (Box 115)
    - Temple, TX, monthly statistics, 1966-1973. (Box 115)
    - Temple, TX, proposed new building, 1967. (Box 115)
    - Temple, TX, self-appraisal study, 1970. (Box 115)
    - Wichita Falls, TX, 1949-1963.; 6 folders. (Box 115)
    - Wichita Falls, TX, audit, 1942. (Box 122)
    - Burlington, VT, audit, 1942. (Box 122)
    - Alexandria, VA, audit, 1942. (Box 122)
    - Alexandria, VA, colored branch, 1941-1942. (Box 115)
    - Blackstone, VA, audit, 1942. (Box 122)
    - Blackstone, VA, opening invitation, 1951. (Box 122)
    - Bowling Green, VA, audit, 1942. (Box 122)
    - Dublin, VA, audit, 1942. (Box 122)
    - Frederisckburg, VA, audit, 1942. (Box 122)
    - Hampton, VA, audit, 1942. (Box 122)
    - Hopewell, VA, audit, 1942. (Box 122)
    - Newport News, VA, audit, 1942. (Box 122)
    - Norfolk, VA, audit, 1942. (Box 123)
    - Norfolk, VA, Tidewater Dr., budget adjustment, 1961. (Box 123)
    - Petersburg, VA, audit, 1942. (Box 123)
    - Portsmouth, VA, 1952-1968.; 3 folders. (Box 115)
    - Portsmouth, VA, audit, 1942. (Box 123)
    - Portsmouth, VA, charter renewal, 1976. (Box 115)
    - Portsmouth, VA, clippings, 1957-1963.; 3 folders. (Box 115)
    - Portsmouth, VA, minutes, 1950-1958.; 3 folders. (Box 115)
    - Portsmouth, VA, minutes, 1958-1959. (Box 116)
    - Portsmouth, VA (African American), 1950-1961. (Box 116)
    - Portsmouth, VA, reports and correspondence, 1945-1957.; 2 folders. (Box 116)
    - Richmond, VA, audits, 1942. (Box 123)
    - Yorktown, VA, audit, 1942. (Box 123)
    - Bremerton, WA (Industrial), monthly statistics, 1943-1946.; 2 folders. (Box 116)
    - Port Angeles, WA, audit, 1942. (Box 123)
    - Port Orchard, WA (Industrial), monthly statistics, 1944-1945. (Box 116)
    - Port Townsend, WA, audit, 1942. (Box 123)
    - Seattle, WA, 1942-1945, 1971-1972.; 2 folders. (Box 116)
    - Seattle, WA, reports and correspondence, 1948-1961. (Box 116)
    - Spokane, WA, 1948-1949, 1960.; 2 folders. (Box 116)
    - Tacoma, WA, 1948-1973.; 6 folders. (Box 116)
    - Tacoma, WA, agreements, 1943-1965. (Box 116)
    - Tacoma, WA, audit, 1942. (Box 123)
    - Tacoma, WA, budget, 1964-1965. (Box 116)
    - Tacoma, WA, clippings, 1961. (Box 116)
    - Tacoma, WA, USO council, 1965. (Box 116)
    - Tacoma, WA, insurance, 1960-1965. (Box 116)
    - Tacoma, WA, military appreciation week, 1967.; 2 folders. (Box 116)
    - Tacoma, WA, survey, 1969. (Box 116)
    - Walla Walla, WA, audit, 1942. (Box 124)
    - Yakima, WA, materials, 1963. (Box 116)
    - Washington, D.C., 1948-1964, 1968-1969.; 3 folders. (Box 116)
    - Washington, D.C., annual report, 1944. (Box 123)
    - Washington, D.C., Lafayette Square USO, 1950-1959.; 2 folders. (Box 116)
    - Washington, D.C., photographs, 1943. (Box 116)
    - Milwaukee, WI, 1970-1974, 1978.; 4 folders. (Box 116)
    - Cheyenne, WY, 1948-1950.; 2 folders. (Box 116)
    - Cheyenne, WY, audit, 1942. (Box 123)
    - Bermuda, history, 1941. (Box 116)
    - Canal Zone, building account, 1921-1924. (Box 116)
    - Canal Zone, building construction, 1922-1941. (Box 116)
    - Canal Zone, committee of management, 1940-1946.; 2 folders. (Box 116)
    - Balboa, Canal Zone, committee of management, 1940-1946. (Box 117)
    - Cristobal, Canal Zone, building plans and materials information, 1923. (Box 117)
    - Cristobal, Canal Zone, committee of management, 1941-1946.; 5 folders. (Box 117)
    - Cristobal, Canal Zone, historical information, 1922-1959.; 2 folders. (Box 117)
    - Cristobal, Canal Zone, three year renovation plan, 1973-1976. (Box 117)
    - Caribbean, 1967. (Box 117)
    - Paris, France, 1970-1972. (Box 117)
    - Athens, Greece, 1973-1974. (Box 117)
    - Guam, 1973-1976.; 2 folders. (Box 117)
    - Naples, Italy, 1964-1971. (Box 117)
    - Vincenza, Italy, 1969-1971. (Box 117)
    - Okinawa, Japan, 1966-1972.; 2 folders. (Box 117)
    - Seoul, Korea, 1976. (Box 117)
    - Philippines, 1949-1962, 1969-1970.; 2 folders. (Box 117)
    - Aguadilla, Puerto Rico, 1941. (Box 117)
    - Bangkok, Thailand, 1972. (Box 117)
    - Korat, Thailand, 1973. (Box 117)
    - Ramasun, Thailand, 1976. (Box 117)
    - Sattahip, Thailand, 1969-1973. (Box 117)
    - U-Tapao, Thailand, 1972-1974. (Box 117)
  - Print Material:
    Contains brochures, pamphlets, newsletters, etc. published by the Army and Navy Department or the International Committee of the YMCA, or by other organizations for distribution in USO clubs.
    - Action on the Industrial USO-YMCA Front, 1944-1945. (Box 117)
    - An Approach to Planning Group Work Services for Returning Servicemen, 1945. (Box 117)
    - The Art of Listening, 1944. (Box 117)
    - Associated Services for the Armed Forces newsletters, 1950-1951. (Box 117)
    - Bataan Corregidor, 1943. (Box 117)
    - Christmas bulletins and newsletters, 1942-1946. (Box 117)
    - The Church and Returning Service Personnel, nos. 2,4, 1944. (Box 117)
    - Church-YMCA Cooperation in the USO, 1944. (Box 117)
    - Community and Campaign Relationships of the USO, 1942. (Box 117)
    - Dealing with Individuals in the USO, undated. (Box 117)
    - The Deeper Significance of the USO, 1942. (Box 117)
    - Field Service Bulletin, 1942. (Box 123)
    - Freedom of the Air, 1944. (Box 117)
    - General Operating Practice, 1944. (Box 117)
    - Hints for Hostesses in Service Clubs, 1944. (Box 117)
    - How to get along in the Service, 1944. (Box 117)
    - I Came Home, undated. (Box 123)
    - Industrial Service News, 1943-1946. (Box 117)
    - Informational materials, undated, 1943, 1957-1960, 1962.; 4 folders. (Box 117)
    - Is God out of Date?, 1945. (Box 117)
    - It is the Christian Faith, 1943. (Box 117)
    - Its up to You, 1947. (Box 117)
    - Its your Choice: how to Choose the Military Service Program that will Serve you Best, 1956. (Box 117)
    - Jobs and Freedom in Post-War America, 1945. (Box 117)
    - The Light is still Shining in the Darkness, 1946. (Box 117)
    - Make the War Strengthen your Marriage, 1944. (Box 117)
    - The Minute Man, 1946. (Box 117)
    - Out!, 1945. (Box 117)
    - Overseas bulletins, 1942. (Box 117)
    - Overseas Flier, 1943. (Box 117)
    - Overseas Flier, 1944-1945. (Box 123)
    - Planning USO Services for the Wives of Servicemen, undated. (Box 117)
    - The Price of Free World Victory, undated. (Box 117)
    - Program by Pros, 1970. (Box 117)
    - Range Finders, 1924, 1941.; 2 folders. (Box 117)
    - Rations 100 Days, 1942. (Box 117)
    - Religious leaflets, circa 1940.; 2 folders. (Box 117)
    - Service Women, undated. (Box 117)
    - Special Service Topics, 1945. (Box 117)
    - USO Services in Communities near Hospitals, 1946. (Box 118)
    - Shall I Marry now?, 1943. (Box 118)
    - Snack Bar Snacks, 1944. (Box 118)
    - Social hygiene pamphlets, 1942-1943. (Box 118)
    - Straight from the Shoulder, 1944. (Box 118)
    - Think on these things, 1941. (Box 118)
    - Tired? What do you know about Fatigue?, 1944. (Box 118)
    - Toward Improved Field Supervision in the USO, 1944. (Box 118)
    - Travel Tips, undated. (Box 118)
    - Tribute: A Round-up of Comment on USOs 5th Anniversary, 1947. (Box 118)
    - 20 Questions: the YMCA in the USO, undated. (Box 118)
    - USO Community Conducted Operations Reporter, April 1943 - October 1946.; 2 folders. (Box 118)
    - USO Educational Activities for the about to return to Civilian Life, 1945. (Box 118)
    - USO Experience and Social Work Practice, 1945. (Box 118)
    - USO Information Notebook for U.S. 6th Fleet and U.S. Armed Forces in Europe, 1962. (Box 118)
    - USO Journal, The, 1974. (Box 118)
    - USO News, The, 1941-1942. (Box 118)
    - USO News/USO Newsletter, 1951-1970. (Box 118)
    - USO News Service, 1949. (Box 118)
    - USO Services to Wives of men in the Armed Forces, undated. (Box 118)
    - USO and the Urban Crisis, 1969. (Box 118)
    - Volunteer brochures, undated. (Box 118)
    - We Believe, 1943. (Box 118)
    - Welcoming the Wounded, 1944. (Box 118)
    - What do we Know to be Right?, 1943. (Box 118)
    - What it takes to do a Good USO Job, 1942. (Box 123)
    - What's Doing?, 1942-1946.; 5 folders. (Box 118)
    - What the War is all about, 1942. (Box 118)
    - When I get out will I find a Job?, 1944. (Box 118)
    - Wherever they Go, 1973-1975. (Box 119)
    - Women after the War, undated. (Box 118)
    - Women in the Service, undated. (Box 118)
    - Working with the Churches in War Industry Communities, 1945. (Box 118)
    - Your Stake in the Occupation, 1946. (Box 118)
RELATED MATERIALS
An extensive series of World War II-era photographs can be found in the Kautz Family YMCA Archives photo collection.
Additional World War II-era photographs as well as scrapbooks can be found in the separately cataloged in the Armed Services Scrapbooks and Photo Albums.
Additional copies of some newspapers and periodicals, as well as additional, related titles are separately cataloged in the Kautz Family YMCA Archives serials collection.
United Service Organizations records of the YWCA National Board are available in the Social Welfare History Archives, University of Minnesota Libraries.
OTHER FINDING AIDS
See the summary inventory for the YMCA Armed Services Records for information on other Armed Services records in the Kautz Family YMCA Archives. >> Go to the summary inventory
INDEX TERMS
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the catalog of the University of Minnesota Libraries. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Topics:
Soldiers -- Recreation.; World War, 1939-1945 -- African Americans.; World War, 1939-1945 -- Newspapers.; World War, 1939-1945 -- War work -- Young Men's Christian Associations.
Places:
United States -- Armed Forces -- Service clubs.; United States -- Armed Forces -- Military life.
Organizations:
National Board of the Young Men's Christian Associations. Armed Services Dept.; National Jewish Welfare Board.; Salvation Army.; United Service Organizations (U.S.) -- Administration.
Types of Documents:
Photographs.